A hometown hero battles a giant corporation to save his city.
Roger & Me is a documentary, history, comedy film directed by Michael Moore.
A documentary about the closure of General Motors' plant at Flint,
Michigan, which resulted in the loss of 30,000 jobs.
Details the attempts of filmmaker Michael Moore to get
an interview with GM CEO Roger Smith.
Self, played by Michael Moore.
Self, played by Rhonda Britton.
Self, played by Fred Ross.
Self, played by Roger B. Smith.
Self, played by Bob Eubanks.
Self, played by James Blanchard.
Roger & Me is a 1989 American documentary film written, produced, directed
by, and starring Michael Moore, in his directorial debut.
Moore portrays the regional economic impact of General Motors CEO Roger Smith's action of closing several auto plants in his
hometown of Flint, Michigan, reducing GM's employees in that area from 80,000 in 1978 to about 50,000 in 1992.
The film won the People's Choice Award at the 14th
Toronto International Film Festival.
In 2013, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of capitalism,
economics, unemployment, corporate greed.
The tone is lighthearted.